Finding aid for the John Fante papers LSC.1832
UCLA Library Special Collections
John Fante papers
circa 1925-2000
UCLA Library Special Collections
Fante, John
LSC.1832
23.5 Linear Feet (47 document boxes and 8 oversize boxes)
John Fante (1909-1983) was an American writer of Italian descent whose depiction of 1930s Los Angeles in his novel Ask the Dust (1939) earned him his greatest acclaim. The work inspired later artists such as Charles Bukowski and Robert Towne. Fante wrote many short stories and novels throughout his life. He also worked as a contract screenwriter for Hollywood studios. The collection consists of manuscripts, publications, correspondence, articles, financial records, ephemera and memorabilia.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Purchase, 2009.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9964950463606533
Biography
John Fante was a writer of short stories, novels, and screenplays. He was born April 8, 1909 in Denver, Colorado to Nick and Mary Fante. John graduated from Regis High School in 1927 and briefly attended the University of Colorado, Boulder before heading to California to embark on his writing career. In 1930 he began a correspondence with the esteemed editor of The American Mercury, H.L. Mencken, who published Fante's first story, "Altar Boy" (1932). Fante's early writings established the central conflicts and themes that would continue to characterize his art. The autobiographically-inflected fiction that he would produce throughout his life most commonly reimagined his struggles with Roman Catholicism, his family, his identification as an ethnic American, and his development as a writer. In the early years of his career, Fante wrote and published many short stories; a collection of these, Dago Red, appeared in 1940. During this time he also wrote three novels: The Road to Los Angeles (ca.1936, published in 1985), Wait Until Spring, Bandini (1938), and Ask the Dust (1939). The novels introduce Fante's major character, Arturo Bandini, and track his psychological and aesthetic development. Prior to the publication of the two novels Fante met Joyce Smart. The two were secretly married in 1937. Joyce would be the greatest advocate for his literary career, not only serving as his first and most trusted reader but also saving the manuscripts, documents, and other records that now constitute the John Fante papers. It was also during the 1930s that Fante began working as a contract screenwriter for various Hollywood studios. Though he disliked the job and believed it detracted him from his literary career, screenwriting made for an intermittently handsome, albeit unstable income. Jeanne Eagels (1957) and A Walk on the Wild Side (1962) are among the more notable films to his credit. Fante wrote the screenplay adaptation of his fourth novel, Full of Life (1952). The resulting film, also called Full of Life (1956), did well both commercially and critically, the only such success of Fante's film career. He continued to publish novels, including one for children, Bravo, Burro! (1970), and The Brotherhood of the Grape (1977). His final work, Dreams from Bunker Hill (1982), concludes the quartet of novels often referred to as the Saga of Arturo Bandini. John Fante died of pneumonia on May 8, 1983 at the Motion Picture and Television Hospital in Woodland Hills, California. Soon afterward, Black Sparrow Press began releasing new editions of Fante's long out-of-print works as well as several previously unpublished novels and short stories: The Wine of Youth (1983), The Road to Los Angeles, West of Rome (1986), 1933 Was a Bad Year (1991), and The Big Hunger: Stories 1932-1959 (2000). Two feature films have been made from Fante's works, Dominique Deruddere's adaptation of Wait Until Spring, Bandini (1989), and Robert Towne's adaptation of Ask the Dust (2006).
Scope and Content
The John Fante Papers range from ca. 1925 to 2000. The papers include manuscripts, printed materials, correspondence, financial records, and assorted ephemera related to Fante's life and career. Manuscripts of The Road to Los Angeles (ca.1936), Wait Until Spring Bandini (1938), and the prologue to Ask the Dust (1939) are included along with those of his others novels and short stories. Other materials include: printed stories and articles, scripts, and letters. The financial records reflect John Fante's personal life and career as an author and screenwriter. These records include items such as contracts, checks, receipts, and income statements. The collection also contains clippings, promotional materials, scrapbooks, and Fante's typewriter.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Writings by John Fante
1.1. Literary Works
1.2. Television, Film, and Radio Scripts
2. Correspondences
2.1. John Fante Correspondences
2.2. Joyce Fante Correspondences
Writings by Others
3.1. Writings by Others Regarding John Fante
3.2. Writings by Others Assorted
Associated Events
Financial Records
5.1. Professional Records
5.2. Income Tax and Personal Expense Records
Personal Records and Materials
Archives; Screenwriters -- United States -- Archives.; Novelists, American -- 20th century -- Archives.; Fante, John
- 1. Writings by John Fante, ca. early 1930s-1986
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains literary, television, film, and radio writings by Fante. Items are arranged chronologically.
  - 1. Literary Works, ca. early 1930s-1986
    - "All-American Team" manuscript, ca. 1930s (Box 1, Folder 1)
      1 manuscript
    - "The Wrath of God" manuscript, ca. 1930s (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "Hail Mary" manuscript, ca. 1930s (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Early Short Stories manuscripts 1 of 2, ca. early 1930s (Box 1, Folder 4)
      13 manuscripts
    - Early Short Stories manuscripts 2 of 2, ca. early 1930s (Box 1, Folder 5)
      7 manuscripts
    - "'Hail Mary' or 'Altar Boy'" manuscript, ca. early 1930s (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "The Road to Los Angeles" manuscript 1 of 2, probably 1936 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "The Road to Los Angeles" manuscript 2 of 2, probably 1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "Wait Until Spring Bandini" manuscript, probably 1938 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - "Wait Until Spring Bandini" outline, breakdown, synopsis, probably 1938 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      8 manuscripts
    - "Prologue to Ask the Dust" manuscript, probably 1939 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - "Prologue to Ask the Dust" edited version, photocopy, 1989, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      1 document, 1 photocopy
    - "Dago Red" manuscript of the play, probably 1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Helen, Thy Beauty is To Me" manuscript, probably 1940 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Grandma versus America" manuscript, probably 1941 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      1 manuscript and one letter
    - "Mary Osaka, I Love You" manuscript, probably 1942 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Little Brown Brothers" manuscript, probably 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      3 manuscripts
    - Untitled children's stories manuscripts, probably 1945 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      6 manuscripts
    - "Papa Christmas Tree" manuscript, probably 1946 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - "The Case of the Haunted Writer" manuscript, probably 1949 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - "The White Balloon" manuscript, ca. early 1950s (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - "Full of Life" manuscript, probably 1951 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - "The Big Hunger" manuscripts, probably 1952 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      2 manuscripts
    - Speech manuscript, probably 1952 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - "In the Spring.. ." manuscript, probably 1953 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - "Les Roses/The Roses" synopsis, probably 1957 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - "The First Time I Saw Paris" manuscript, probably 1959 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - "The Left-Handed Virgin" manuscript version A, ca. early 1960s (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - "The Left-Handed Virgin" manuscript version B, ca. early 1960s (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - "The Left-Handed Virgin" manuscript version C, ca. early 1960s (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - "The Left-Handed Virgin" manuscript version D, ca. early 1960s (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - "The Left-Handed Virgin" manuscript version E, ca. early 1960s (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - "The Left-Handed Virgin" manuscript version F, ca. early 1960s (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - "The Left-Handed Virgin" manuscript version G, ca. early 1960s (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - "The Left-Handed Virgin" manuscript version H & I, ca. early 1960s (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - "1933 Was a Bad Year" manuscript 1 of 2, ca. early 1960s (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - "1933 Was a Bad Year" manuscript 2 of 2, ca. early 1960s (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - "The Left-Handed Virgin/1933 Was a Bad Year" synopses, ca. early 1960s (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - "The Confusion of the Times or A Change of Life" manuscripts, probably 1966 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - "My Father's God" manuscripts, probably 1966 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - "My Dog Stupid" manuscripts version A and B, probably 1966 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - "My Dog Stupid" manuscript version C 1 of 3, probably 1977 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - "My Dog Stupid" manuscript version C 2 of 3, probably 1977 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - "My Dog Stupid" manuscript version C 3 of 3, probably 1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - "The Last Supper" manuscripts, ca. 1974-1977 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - "The Brotherhood of the Grape" manuscript version A, ca. 1974-1977 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - "The Brotherhood of the Grape" manuscript version B, ca. 1974-1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - "The Brotherhood of the Grape" manuscript version C, ca. 1974-1977 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - "The Brotherhood of the Grape" manuscript version D 1 of 2, ca. 1974-1977 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - "The Brotherhood of the Grape" manuscript version D 2 of 2, ca. 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - "The Brotherhood of the Grape" manuscript version E 1 of 2, ca. 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - "The Brotherhood of the Grape" manuscript version E 2 of 2, ca. 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - "The Brotherhood of the Grape" manuscript version F, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - John Fante's Dictations to Joyce Fante, ca. late 1970s (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - "Dreams from Bunker Hill" manuscript 1 of 8, ca. 1979-1982 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - "Dreams from Bunker Hill" manuscript 2 of 8, ca. 1979-1982 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - "Dreams from Bunker Hill" manuscript 3 of 8, ca. 1979-1982 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - "Dreams from Bunker Hill" manuscript 4 of 8, ca. 1979-1982 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - "Dreams from Bunker Hill" manuscript 5 of 8, ca. 1979-1982 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - "Dreams from Bunker Hill" manuscript 6 of 8, ca. 1979-1982 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - "Dreams from Bunker Hill" manuscript 7 of 8, ca. 1979-1982 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - "Dreams from Bunker Hill" manuscript 8 of 8, ca. 1979-1982 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - "Dreams from Bunker Hill" proof, probably 1982 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      1 proof
    - "A Bad Woman" manuscript, no date (Box 8, Folder 2)
      1 manuscript, 1 photocopy
    - Early short stories manuscripts, ca. early 1930s (Box 8, Folder 3)
      4 manuscripts
    - Fragments, no dates (Box 8, Folder 4)
      29 manuscripts
    - "I am a Writer of Truth" manuscript, probably 1936 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - "Mama's Dream" manuscript, ca. late 1940s (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Notes 1 of 2, no dates (Box 8, Folder 7)
      10 manuscripts, 3 notepads
    - Notes 2 of 2, no dates (Box 8, Folder 8)
      4 notepads
    - "The Orgy" manuscripts 1 of 2, no dates (Box 8, Folder 9)
      5 manuscripts
    - "The Orgy" manuscripts 2 of 2, no dates (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - "Shakedown" manuscript, no date (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - "The Sled" manuscript, no date (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - "The Tears of Tito Tetto" manuscript, no date (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified works manuscripts, no dates (Box 9, Folder 5)
      9 manuscripts
    - "Altar Boy" published work, 1932 August (Box 9, Folder 6)
      1 clipping
    - "Home, Sweet Home" published work, 1932 November (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - "Big Leaguer" published work, probably 1932 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - "The Odyssey of a Wop" published work, 1933 September (Box 9, Folder 9)
      3 clippings
    - "One of Us" published work, 1934 October (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - "The Road to Hell" published work, 1937 October (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - "A Nun No More" published works, probably 1940 October; 1952 Autumn (Box 9, Folder 12)
      4 clippings
    - "Mary Osaka, I Love You" published work, 1942 October (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - "Helen, Thy Beauty Is to Me" published work, 1941 March 1 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      2 magazines
    - "The Taming of Valenti" published work, 1941 April (Box 10, Folder 2)
      1 magazine
    - "The Scoundrel" published work, 1945 March (Box 10, Folder 3)
      1 clipping, 2 magazines
    - "Papa Christmas Tree" published work, 1946 December (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - "The Dreamer" published work, 1947 June (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - "The Wine of Youth" published work, 1948 December (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - "One-Play Oscar" published work, 1950 November (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - "In the Spring" published work, 1952 March 15 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - "The Big Hunger" published work, 1952 August 2 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - "The Odyssey of a Wop" published work, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - "Ask the Dust" excerpt published work, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "Helen, Thy Beauty is To Me" galley, no date (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - "Full of Life" galley, no date (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - "Bravo, Burro!" galley 1 of 2, no date (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - "Bravo, Burro!" galley 2 of 2, no date (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - "The Brotherhood of the Grape" galley 1 of 2, no date (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - "The Brotherhood of the Grape" galley 2 of 2, no dates (Box 12, Folder 7)
      2 proofs
    - "Altar Boy" published work, 1932 August (Box 38, Folder 4)
      1 magazine, 1 photocopy of cover
    - "Home Sweet Home" published work, 1932 November (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - "First Communion" published work 1 of 2, 1933 February (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - "First Communion" published work 2 of 2, 1933 February (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - "Big Leaguer" published work, 1933 March (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - "The Odyssey of a Wop" published work, 1933 September (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - "Bricklayer in the Snow" published work, 1936 January (Box 39, Folder 2)
      1 magazine, 1 note
    - "Swords and Roses.. ." article, 1936 October 2 (Box 39, Folder 3)
      1 clipping, 3 photocopies
    - "We Snatch a Frail" published work, 1936 November 2 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      1 photocopy
    - "The Postman Rings and Rings" published work, 1937 March (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - "Charge It" published work, 1937 April (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - "None So Blind" published work, 1938 April (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - "A Nun No More!" published work, 1940 Autumn (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - "Bill Saroyan" published work, 1941 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - "That Wonderful Bird" published work, 1941 May (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - "Helen, Thy Beauty is to Me" published work, 1958 October (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - "John Fante on L.A. from tape" typescript, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 12)
      2 copies
    - "Dreams from Bunker Hill" excerpt, published work, 1980 September (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Preface for "Wait Until Spring, Bandini" typescript and manuscript, 1981 May 11 (Box 39, Folder 14)
      1 typescript, 1 manuscript
    - "A Diamond of Years: The Best of the Woman's Home Companion" book, 1961 (Box 50, Folder 3)
      1 book
    - "The Brotherhood of the Grape" parts 1 and 2, 1975 July 6-11 (Box 53, Folder 5)
      4 magazines
    - "The Brotherhood of the Grape" parts 3 and 4, 1975 July 20-27 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - "The Brotherhood of the Grape" conclusion, 1975 August 3 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - "Wait Until Spring, Bandini", 1985 December (Box 53, Folder 8)
      2 newspapers
  - 2. Television, Film, and Radio Scripts, probably 1939-1971
    - "Ask the Dust" adaptation, probably 1939 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      3 items
    - "Love Story" screenplay, 1941 July 31 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - "Woman is Fickle" screenplay, 1941 August 12 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      1 item
    - Scripts, 1941 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - "My Friend Bonito" shooting script, 1941 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      2 items
    - "Home is the Hunter" treatment, ca. 1941-1942 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - "Flamenco" treatment, 1945 February 7 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - "For the Love of Picaro" treatment, 1945 May 26 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - "A Panty-Girdle for Mrs. Illytch" treatment, probably 1948 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - "The Long Nightmare" treatment, probably 1948 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - "Letter from the President" treatment, probably 1950 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - "Silver Lode" treatment and step outline, 1952 May-June (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - "Orca" treatment and scenario script, 1952 August-September (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - "Saints Alive" teleplay for series, 1 of 2, probably 1953 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      4 items
    - "Saints Alive" teleplay for series, 2 of 2, probably 1953 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - "The Second Thief" teleplay, probably 1954 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - "Miracle of the Fishes" treatment, 1955 February 10 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - "A Hero Returns" teleplay, 1955 November-December (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - "Full of Life" screenplay, 1956 February 2 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - "Full of Life" incomplete screenplays, 1956 March 30 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - "Full of Life" screenplay, 1956 April 18 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - "Les Roses" screenplay, 1956 November 6 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - "Jeanne Eagels" screenplay, 1956 December to 1957 February (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - "Les Roses" screenplay, 1957 June 27 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - "The Roses" synopsis, 1958 January 14 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - "Les Roses" screenplay, 1958 February 13 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - "High Tide" screenplay, 1959 March 26 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - "Papa" teleplay 1 of 6, probably 1959 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - "Papa" teleplay 2 of 6, 1959 November (Box 15, Folder 8)
      5 items
    - "Papa" teleplay 3 of 6, 1959 November (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - "Papa" teleplay 4 of 6, 1959 November (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - "Papa" teleplay 5 of 6, 1959 November (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - "Papa" teleplay 6 of 6, 1959 November (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - "The Hour of Saint Francis" screenplay, ca. mid to late 1950s (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - "Mother Cabrini" feature script, ca. mid to late 1950s (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - "Saint of the Satellites" screenplay, ca. mid to late 1950s (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - "Thorn in the Flesh" treatment 1 of 3, ca. mid to late 1950s (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - "Thorn in the Flesh" treatment 2 of 3, ca. mid to late 1950s (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - "Thorn in the Flesh" treatment 3 of 3, ca. mid to late 1950s (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - "Black City/King of Poggioreale" screenplay, 1960 November 17 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - "Walk on the Wild Side" screenplay, probably 1961 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - "Walk on the Wild Side" screenplay, final draft, 1961 March 14 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - "My Six Loves" screenplay, 1961 October 9 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - "The Reluctant Saint" screenplay photocopy, probably 1962 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - "The Reluctant Saint" screenplay, probably 1962 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - "Captain Al Sanchez" teleplay, 1963 October 2 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - "Maya" screenplay first draft, 1964 February 1 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - "Maya" screenplay second draft, 1964 April 1 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - "Gold in the Streets" treatment, 1964 May 5 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - "Maya" screenplay revised drafts, 1964 June, August (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - "Father of the Son" screenplay, 1964 August 18 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - "Maya the Magnificent" synopsis, 1964 September 22 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - "Maya" presentation and script, probably 1964 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - "Maya" reel notes, 1965 July (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - "King of the Wind" screenplay 1 of 2, 1965 November 18 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - "King of the Wind" screenplay 2 of 2, 1965 November 18 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - "Black Mountain" treatment, probably 1965 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - "King of the Wind" screenplay, 1966 April 12 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - "Something for a Lonely Man" screenplay 1 of 3, 1967 June 12 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - "Something for a Lonely Man" screenplay 2 of 3, probably 1967 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - "Something for a Lonely Man" screenplay 3 of 3, probably 1967 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - "A Man is Better Than a Town" treatment, 1968 August 19 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - "My Dog Stupid" television treatment, ca. late 1960s (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - "My Dog Stupid" screenplay, probably 1971 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - "Are These Our Children" treatment, no date (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - "Assassin" screenplay notes, no date (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - "The Ballad of Whistler's Mother" screenplay, no date (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - "The Betrayed" screenplay 1 of 3, no date (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - "The Betrayed" screenplay 2 of 3, no date (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - "The Betrayed" screenplay 3 of 3, no date (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - "The Chicanos" television series treatment, no date (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - "Chinese Gordon" treatment, no date (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - "Christmas with the Padre Choristers" script, no date (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - "Dancer on the Run" step outline, no date (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - "The Dark Laughter" treatment, no date (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - "The Dark Mountain" treatment, no date (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - "Dr. Jackal and Mr. Hide" treatment, no date (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - "Dust" screenplay, no date (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - "The Fabulous Feud" teleplay, no date (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Fragments (Television, Film, Radio), no date (Box 21, Folder 12)
      19 items
    - "Gloria in Excelsior" treatment, no date (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - "The Golden Gown" treatment 1 of 4, no date (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - "The Golden Gown" treatment 2 of 4, no date (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - "The Golden Gown" treatment 3 of 4, no date (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - "The Golden Gown" treatment 4 of 4, no date (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - "The Great Diamond Hoax" outline, no date (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - "The Hispano Blondes" screenplay 1 of 2, no date (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - "The Hispano Blondes" screenplay 2 of 2, no date (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - "How to Kill a President" screenplay, no date (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - "Joey Jekyll" presentation for television series, no date (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - "The Lawbringers" screenplay, no date (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - "Lisa" screenplay, no date (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - "Magna Cum Laude" screenplay, no date (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - "Mister Mustache" treatment, no date (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - "The New World of Carmen Colombo" treatment, no date (Box 23, Folder 7)
      7 items
    - "The New World of Carmen Colombo" script notes, no date (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Notes, no date (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - "The Rialto Kid" treatment, no date (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - "Roughing It" screenplay, no date (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - "The Stroke" screenplay, no date (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - "Thunder in the South" screenplay, no date (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - "The Trouble with Carmen" treatment, no date (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - "Two for the Money" treatment, no date (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - "The Two Lives of Sam Salem" treatment, no date (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified works, 1954,1955 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - "Vicksburg" treatment, no date (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - "The Walls of Heaven" treatment 1 of 2, no date (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - "The Walls of Heaven" treatment 2 of 2, no date (Box 24, Folder 7)
- 2. Correspondences, 1932-1998
  Contains correspondences with John Fante and his wife Joyce Fante. Items are arranged alphabetically.
  - 1. John Fante Correspondences, 1932-1998
    - Miscellany, 1932-1998 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      13 items
    - A-B, 1935-1982 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      85 items